Finding Aid for Frank Manny papers 1890-1955
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Frank Manny papers 1890-1955
Manny, Frank Addison, 1868-1954.
852267 Aa 2
Progressive educator, student of Thomas Dewey at the University of Chicago, served as head of the state Normal School at Oshkosh, Wisconsin, superintendent of the Felix Adler School of Ethical Culture in New York City and as head of teacher education in the city of Baltimore. The papers include extensive personal correspondence, scrapbooks, journals, writings and other materials concerning his professional interests. Correspondence includes letters from distinguished authors and educators.
6 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
This collection is a gift of the Estate of Frank Addison Manny of Boxford, Massachusetts. Paul S. Harris, Executor. It was received at the library in February 1956. Donor no. 3191
The collection is open for research.
Frank Addison Manny was a progressive educator who believed in applying "an attitude of inquiry" to the classroom. Manny explored the philosophical, psychological, and moral dimensions of pedagogy and learning. As a critic of standardization, he was interested in the practical benefits of experimental education and in adapting industrial education to workers' concerns.
Born in Mounds, Illinois on June 24, 1868, Manny was raised in Michigan City, Indiana. He earned a Bachelor of Arts from the University of Michigan in 1893 and, in 1896, a Master of Arts. On June 24, 1904, Manny married Annette Sawyer. He died in 1954.
Manny held several positions during the course of his career as a teacher and trainer of teachers. Manny was hired as a high school principal in Moline, Illinois in 1894. During his two years there, he established an extension program for the education of factory workers. From 1896 to 1897, Manny worked at the University of Chicago as an assistant in pedagogy to Professor John Dewey, a philosopher and educational theorist whose writings had an impact on educational reform internationally. In Chicago, Manny studied the university's Experimental School whose classrooms, according to Dewey's principles, broke with formal curricula and attempted to relate ideas to practical life.
During the academic year starting in the fall of 1897, Manny was the supervisor of public schools in Indianapolis, Indiana. Then, from 1998 to 1900, he headed Wisconsin's State Normal School, based in Oshkosh. He subsequently moved to New York City where, for six years, he was superintendent of the Felix Adler School of Ethical Culture.
Returning to Michigan in 1908, Manny headed the education and extension departments of Western State Normal School in Kalamazoo until 1911. He also directed and taught at the Allegany County (Maryland) Teachers' Continuation School from 1909 to 1911. Settling permanently in the East, Manny became the director of teacher training for the city of Baltimore (1911 to 1915).
In 1915, Manny directed his interests to the effects of malnutrition. For three years, he studied and reported upon the nutrition of children and families for the Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor in New York City. He subsequently did similar work in Boston in collaboration with Dr. William R.P. Emerson.
During his professional life, Manny contributed articles to educational journals and magazines that addressed social topics. He briefly contracted with the United States Bureau of Education, for which he wrote a brochure, City Training Schools for Teachers (1914). Manny lectured widely about education issues as well as such topics as his support of women's suffrage, the importance of inspecting private and parochial schools, and the effectiveness of curfews. Manny also wrote dozens of poems, some of which were published.
Manny did extensive research into the folklore and genealogy of the people of Boxford, Massachusetts, the small town in which he and his wife settled. Many of Manny's findings and musings about this community were published in his North Shore Breeze columns. He also authored Boxfordians in 1923, Boxford Genealogies in 1926, and Time Will Tell--A Tercentenary Pageant in 1930.
Manny was active in a number of social and professional organizations, among them the American Association for the Advancement of Science; Child Welfare League in New York; Committee on Training for Social Service; Just Government League; Men's League for Women's Suffrage; National Education Association; NAACP; Phi Beta Kappa; Prisoners' Aid Society; School Arts League; Social Workers' Bureau; Society for Ethical Culture; and the YMCA Educational Committee. Manny also served on the editorial board of the Atlantic Educational Journal and the advisory boards for the Journal of Educational Psychology and the School Journal.
Frank Addison Manny's papers are divided into five series: Clippings, Lectures, and Writings; Correspondence; Photographs; Scrapbooks; and Journals.
The papers consist of extensive personal correspondence, scrapbooks, journals, writings and other materials concerning his professional interests. Included are, letters from distinguished authors and educators. Much of the collection relates to the progressive education movement and to Manny's career as an educator in Grand Rapids, Chicago, and Boxford, Massachusetts.
Subjects:
Academic freedom.; Boxford (Mass.); Chicago (Ill.); Education.; Grand Rapids (Mich.); Judaism.; Manny, Annette Sawyer.; Manny, Frank Addison, 1868-1954.; Religion.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Manny, Frank Addison, 1868-1954.
Contributors:
Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching.; Adamic, Louis, 1899-1951.; Adams, Henry Carter, 1851-1921.; Adams, James Truslow, 1878-1949.; Addams, Jane, 1860-1935.; Adler, Felix, 1851-1933.; Agassiz, Mabel.; Allen, Devere, 1891-1955.; Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.; Angell, James Rowland, 1869-1949.; Asbury, Hubert, 1891-1963.; Austin, Mary Hunter, 1868-1934.; Aydelotte, Frank, 1880-1956.; Ayres, Clarence Edwin, 1891-1972.; Baker, George Pierce, 1866-1935.; Baker, Ray Stannard, 1870-1946.; Barrows, Alice P.; Barton, Bruce, 1886-1967.; Barzun, Jacques, 1907-2012; Bates, George Joseph, 1891-1949.; Baxter, James Phinney, 1893-1975; Beard, Charles Austin, 1874-1948.; Becker, May Lamberton, 1873-1958.; Belding, Anson Wood.; Beston, Henry, 1888-1968.; Bingham, Walter Van Dyke, 1880-1952.; Bishop, William Warner, 1871-1955.; Bliven, Bruce, 1889-1977.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942.; Bodley, J. H.; Bolton, Charles Knowles, 1867-1950.; Bradford, Gamaliel, 1863-1932.; Brasch, Frederick E. (Frederick Edward), 1875-1967.; Bridgman, P. W. (Percy Williams), 1882-1961.; Briggs, Le Baron Russell, 1855-1934.; Bristow, Gwen, 1903-; Brittain, Vera, 1893-1970.; Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963.; Brown, Elmer Ellsworth, 1861-1934.; Brown, Henry B., 1847-1917.; Brush, Katharine, 1902-1952.; Bryan, William Lowe, 1860-1955.; Buck, Gertrude, 1871-1922.; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973.; Burgess, Thornton W. (Thornton Waldo), 1874-1965.; Burnham, William Henry, 1855-1941.; Burritt, Balley Barton, 1878-1954.; Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947.; Butterfield, Kenyon L. (Kenyon Leech), 1868-1935.; Cabot, William Brooks, 1858-1949.; Canby, Henry Seidel, 1878-1961.; Caplan, Abraham.; Carhart, Henry S. (Henry Smith), 1844-1920.; Carrel, Alexis, 1873-1944.; Carroll, Gladys Hasty, 1904-1999; Cathcart, C. C.; Catlin, George B. (George Byron), 1857-1934.; Charters, W. W. (Werrett Wallace), 1875-1952.; Chase, Mary Ellen, 1887-1973.; Childs, Harold Farnsworth.; Churchill, Alfred Vance, 1864-1934.; Claxton, Philander Priestley, 1862-1957.; Conant, James Bryant, 1893-1978.; Connick, Charles Jay, 1875-1945.; Corwin, E. H. L. (Edward Henry Lewinski), 1885-1953; Cowley, Malcolm, 1898-1989.; Cram, Ralph Adams, 1863-1942.; Cross, Ira Brown, 1880-; Cullen, Countee, 1903-1946.; Cullen, Yolande Dubois.; Dabney, Virginius, 1901-1995; Daly, Arnold, 1875-1927.; Dana, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, 1881-1950.; Daniels, Jonathan, 1902-1981; Darden, Colgate W. (Colgate Whitehead), 1897-1981.; Davenport, Charles Benedict, 1866-1944.; Dawson, Percy M. (Percy Millard), 1873-; Deland, Margaret Wade Campbell, 1857-1945.; Demmon, Isaac Newton, 1842-1920.; Deutsch, Babette, 1895-1982; Dewey, John, 1859-1952.; Dieffenbach, Albert C.; D'Ooge, Martin Luther, 1839-1915.; Dresser, Horatio W. (Horatio Willis), b. 1866.; Du Bois, W. E. B. (William Edward Burghardt), 1868-1963.; Dunbar, Daphne.; Dutton, Samuel Train, 1849-1919.; Dykema, Peter W. (Peter William), 1873-1951.; Eastman, Max, 1883-1969.; Easton, Emily.; Edgell, George Harold, 1887-1954; Eliot, Thomas H. (Thomas Hopkinson), 1907-1991; Engel, Leonard, 1916-1964.; English, Colin.; Evans, Elizabeth Glendower, 1856-1937.; Farrell, Charles H., 1873-; Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1879-1958.; Flexner, Abraham, 1866-1959.; Folks, Homer, 1867-1963.; Frank, Glenn, 1887-1940.; Frank, Waldo David, 1889-1967.; Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965.; Fuess, Claude Moore, 1885-1963.; Garland, Hamlin, 1860-1940.; Gavit, John Palmer, 1868-1954.; Gibson, Emily S. Gilbert.; Gleason, Arthur, 1878-1923.; Goodspeed, Charles E. (Charles Eliot), 1867-1950.; Graham, Frank Porter, 1886-1972; Granstead, Durand.; Grant, Wilbur H.; Guerard, Albert Leon, 1880-1959.; Hailmann, W. N. (William Nicholas), 1836-1920.; Hall, G. Stanley (Granville Stanley), 1844-1924.; Halsey, R. H.; Hapgood, Norman, 1868-1937.; Hard, Anne.; Hard, William, 1878-1962.; Harper, William Rainey, 1856-1906.; Hart, Joseph K. (Joseph Kinmont), 1876-1949; Hartzell, Morton C., Mrs.; Haynes, Royal Storrs, 1877-; Henderson, C. Hanford (Charles Hanford), 1861-1941; Herrick, Cheesman Abiah, 1866-1956.; Herron, George Davis, 1862-1925.; Heyward, DuBose, 1885-1940.; Hicks, Granville, 1901-1982; Higginson, Mary Potter Thacher, 1844-1941.; Hocking, William Ernest, 1873-1966.; Holbrook, Stewart Hall, 1893-1964.; Holtzoff, Alexander, 1886-1969; Hopkins, Ernest Martin, 1877-1964.; Howe, A. A. DeWolfe.; Hoxie, Robert Franklin, 1868-1916.; Hunt, Jean Lee.; James, Edmund J. (Edmund Janes), 1855-1925.; James, Howard M.; Jennings, H. S. (Herbert Spencer), 1868-1947.; Johnston, Eric A. (Eric Allen), 1895-1963.; Kelley, Florence, 1859-1932.; Kidd, Thomas I.; Kirstein, Louis Edward, 1867-1942.; LaFetra, Linnaeus Edford, 1868-; Lane, Gertrude.; Lane, Rose Wilder, 1886-1968.; Lanier, Charles D., Mrs.; Laski, Harold Joseph, 1893-1950.; Lefavour, Henry, 1862-1946.; Lerner, Max, 1902-1992; Lewisohn, Ludwig, 1882-1955.; Lilienthal, David Eli, 1899-1981.; Linville, Henry R. (Henry Richardson), 1866-1941; Lippmann, Walter, 1889-1974.; Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1902-1985; Lord, Russell, 1895-1964.; Lovett, Robert Morss, 1870-1956.; Lowell, A. Lawrence (Abbott Lawrence), 1856-1943.; MacLean, Eugene.; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982.; MacMillan, D. P.; MacNeill, Ben Dixon, 1889-1960.; Malone, Dumas, 1892-1986; Mann, Charles Riborg, 1869-1942.; Marks, Jeannette Augustus, 1875-1964.; Marquand, John P. (John Phillips), 1893-1960.; Marshall, Margaret.; Martin, George H. (George Henry), 1841-1917.; Mather, Kirtley F. (Kirtley Fletcher), 1888-1978; Mead, George Herbert, 1863-1931.; Meiklejohn, Alexander, 1872-1964.; Mertz, David Franklin, d. 1900.; Metcalf, Elinor Gregory.; Mills, Benjamin Fay, 1857-1916.; Monroe, Paul, 1869-1947.; Morgan, Arthur Ernest, 1878-1975.; Morgan, James.; Morison, Samuel Eliot, 1887-1976.; Morley, Felix, 1894-; Morris, Lloyd R., 1893-1954.; Mott, John Raleigh, 1865-1955.; Muldoon, William.; Mumford, Lewis, 1895-1990.; Munsterberg, Margarete Anna Adelheid, 1889-; Murrg, F. M.; Mussey, Henry Raymond, 1875-1940.; Nichols, Walter Hammond, 1866-1935.; Oppenheim, James, 1882-1932.; O'Shea, Michael Vincent, 1866-1932.; Palmer, Frank Herbert, 1853-1936.; Palmer, George Herbert, 1842-1933.; Parker, Francis W. (Francis Wayland), 1837-1902.; Partridge, Bellamy, 1877-1960; Patten, Simon Nelson, 1852-1922.; Payne, E. George (Enoch George), 1877-1953; Pearl, Edward E.; Peattie, Donald Culross, 1898-1964.; Perry, Clarence Arthur, 1872-1944; Perry, Maude Elaine Caldwell, 1873-1963.; Phelps, William Lyon, 1865-1943.; Phillips, James Duncan, b. 1876.; Porter, Kenneth.; Pressey, Edward Pearson.; Price, Lucien, 1883-1964.; Putnam, William Lowell, Mrs., 1862-1935.; Rannells, B. U.; Richardson, Hilary Goode, 1874-; Rogers, Will, 1911-1993; Rolfe, John Carew, 1859-1943.; Roosevelt, James, 1907-1991; Roper, Richard F.; Rowe, Stuart H.; Rugg, Winnifred King.; Rumely, Edward A. (Edward Aloysius), 1882-1964; Russell, James E. (James Earl), 1864-1945; Saint-Gaudens, Homer, 1880-1958; Sancton, Thomas Wolfe, 1915-; Sanford, Daniel Sammis, 1859-1936.; Sargent, Walter, 1868-1929; Savage, Toy Dixon, 1878-1941.; Saxon, Lyle, 1891-1946.; Sayre, Francis Bowes, 1885-1972.; Schaeffer, Mary F.; Schwartz-Buys, E.; Scott, Fred Newton, 1860-1931.; Scudder, Myron Tracy, 1860-1935.; Seabrook, William, b. 1887.; Seashore, Carl E. (Carl Emil), 1866-1949.; Sedgwick, Ellery, 1872-1960.; Seymour, Charles, 1885-1963.; Shaw, Paula A.; Shepard, Odell, 1884-1967.; Slosson, Edwin Emery, 1865-1929.; Slosson, Preston W. (Preston William), 1892-1984; Smith, Glanville.; Smith, Lillian Eugenia, 1897-1966.; Smith, Thomas Vernor, 1890-1964.; Snedden, David, 1868-1951; South, Lloyd V.; Spencer, Anna Garlin, 1851-1931.; Stark, Otto, 1859-1926.; Steele, Thomas Clement, 1847-1926.; Stein, Clarence S.; Storrow, Helen Osborne.; Suzzallo, Henry, 1875-1933.; Swift, Edgar James, 1860-1932.; Talbert, Edward.; Talbot, Marion, 1858-1948.; Tarbell, Ida M. (Ida Minerva), 1857-1944.; Taylor, Graham, 1851-1938.; Thomas, Lowell, 1892-1981.; Todd, J. Liberty.; Traubel, Horace, 1858-1919.; Triggs, Oscar Lovell, 1865-1930.; Tyner, Paul.; Untermeyer, Louis, 1885-1977.; Valbin, Joseph.; Van Doren, Mark, 1894-1972.; Villard, Oswald Garrison, 1872-1949.; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar), 1864-1941.; Waln, Nora.; Walsh, David Ignatius, 1872-1947.; Washington, Booker T., 1856-1915.; Watson, Goodwin, 1899-1976; Weygandt, Cornelius, 1871-1957.; Whipple, Guy Montrose, 1876-1941.; White, Stewart Edward, 1873-1946.; Whiting, Lilian, 1847-1942.; Wieffenbach, Albert C.; Wilcox, Delos F. (Delos Franklin), 1873-1928.; Wilson, Edmund, 1895-1972.; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924.; Wolfe, Rolland, 1902-; Woodberry, George Edward, 1855-1930.; Woodbridge, Homer E. (Homer Edwards), 1882-1958; Woodward, C. Vann (Comer Vann), 1908-1999; Woolf, Virginia, 1882-1941.; Yarmolinsky, Avrahm, 1890-1975; Young, Ella Flagg, 1845-1918.; Zelenko, A. V.; Zueblin, Charles, 1866-1924.
Genre/Form:
Diaries.; Photographic prints.
- Clippings, Lectures and Writings
  The Clippings, Lectures, and Writings series consists of Manny's writings as well as of those he assembled from and about Professor John Dewey, writer James Oppenheim, and Rolland E. Wolfe. The Manny subseries consists primarily of his own published and unpublished writings, with one folder of clippings about Manny. Also included are two folders of clippings with no consistent theme. A complementary collection of Manny's writings, including his poetry, and of clippings about his professional and community activities is available in the Scrapbooks series.
  The Dewey subseries includes detailed notes of Dewey's lectures on such topics as the ethical principals underlying education, the history of modern ethical ideas, moral and political philosophy, and social psychology. Rolland Wolfe's memorial address for Annette and Frank Manny provides a personal perspective on its honorees' characters and interests.
  - Dewey, John
    - Articles by Dewey (Box 1)
    - Clippings about Dewey (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 1)
    - Notes from lectures, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Manny, Frank A.
    - Articles and Poems
      - Miscellaneous, published (Box 1)
      - North Shore Breeze columns 1929-1950, undated (Box 1)
      - Poems (Box 1)
    - Boxford, Massachusetts materials, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Clippings
      - Clippings about Manny (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - "Study of Malnutrition," 1915 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - "Philosophy of Education," lectures (Box 1)
    - Schools (brochures and notes) (Box 1)
  - Oppenheim, James
    - Clippings about Oppenheim (Box 1)
    - Poems and Short Stories
      - Manuscripts (Box 1)
      - Published materials (clippings) (Box 1)
      - "The Three" (short story) manuscript (Box 1)
  - Wolfe, Rolland Emerson
    - "Annette Sawyer Manny and Frank Addison Manny: In Memoriam," Address 1955 (Box 1)
    - Articles, sermons, and miscellaneous writings (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  The Correspondence series includes family letters and letters concerning Manny's professional connections with a large number of distinguished correspondents, particularly among contemporary American authors and leaders in the field of education. The series, which is partially indexed, is arranged chronologically. The Undated folders also include letters with missing pages.
  - 1878-1905, 18 folders (Box 1)
  - 1906-1940, 44 folders (Box 2)
  - 1941-1953, 26 folders (Box 3)
  - Undated (Box 3)
  - Dewey, John and Mrs. Alice Dewey (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous correspondents, 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Oppenheim, James (Box 3)
- Photographs
  The Photographs series consists of prints assembled primarily from the Correspondence files; a notation about which letter each was appended has been made when possible. Though there are no photographs of Frank Manny in this series, the Scrapbooks series includes several newspaper clippings with Manny's photograph.
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
- Scrapbooks
  The four volumes of Scrapbooks are organized thematically. Two scrapbooks compile articles written by Manny. The first houses articles spanning 37 years, written chiefly about education and other professional issues. Included here is a talk or article Manny wrote in honor of John Dewey's seventieth birthday, "Democracy and Internationalism." Also included is a copy of Manny's City Training Schools for Teachers (1914), book reviews, and his later work on nutrition.
  The second scrapbook of his articles consists of those that appeared in the North Shore Breeze; these include book reviews, opinion pieces about the topics of the day, and information about Boxford, Massachusetts. Articles and clippings about Manny comprise a third scrapbook, and Manny's collection of his own and others' poetry comprise the fourth. Manny compiled a partial index on the last pages of some of these scrapbooks.
  - Articles and Clippings by and about Manny 1892-1933 (Box 4)
  - Articles by Manny
    - 1895-1932 (Box 4)
    - North Shore Breeze 1928-1931 (Box 4)
  - Poems (Box 4)
- Journals
  Manny's Journals include a range of materials: selective incoming and outgoing correspondence; analysis of literature; personal musings or opinions on political events; anecdotes and remembered dreams; and notes about Boxford. The handwritten and typewritten journals are not redundant. Manny apparently maintained both volumes simultaneously for a period, though during some years, such as 1933, he recorded substantially more material in the handwritten volume than in the typewritten.
  - Handwritten
    - 1932 (Box 4)
    - 1933 (Box 4)
    - 1934 (Box 4)
    - 1937 (Box 4)
    - Perennial Diary 1890-1947 (Box 4)
  - Typewritten
    - 1922-1942, 11 volumes (Box 5)
    - 1943-1950, 6 volumes (Box 6)
Selective Index to Correspondence
Adamic, Louis, 1899-1951.
Jan. 26, 1937; Oct. 30, 1937; June 18, 1938; May 30, 1940; June 25, 1942
Adams, Henry Carter, 1851-1921.
Mar. 14, 1895
Adams, James Truslow, 1878-1949.
Oct. 24, 1935
Addams, Jane, 1860-1935.
Feb. 1, 1908
Adler, Felix, 1851-1933.
Apr. 28, 1900; Oct. 4, 1906
Agassiz, Mabel.
Jan. 7, 1920; Feb. 18, 1920
Allen, Devere.
Feb. 10, 1930
Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.
Feb. 27, 1896; Apr. 6, 1900; Apr. 7, 1900; May 28, 1900; Apr. 17, 1902; June 11, 1903; Feb. 22, 1905; Jan. 15, 1907; Mar. 10, 1908; Dec. 22, 1908
Angell, James Rowland, 1869-1949.
Mar. 14, 1909; July 26, 1912; May 31, 1915; Mar. 3, 1928
Asbury, Herbert, 1891-1963.
Dec. 4, 1937
Austin, Mary (Hunter), 1868-1934.
Jan. 1930
Aydelatte, Frank, 1880-1956.
Nov. 24, 1936
Ayres, Clarence Edwin, 1891-.
Jan. 28, 1939
Baker, George Pierce, 1866-1935.
Dec. 29, 1927
Baker, Ray Stannard, 1870-1946.
Jan. 7, 1946
Barrows, Alice P.
Apr. 10, 1906
Barton, Bruce, 1886-.
July 18, 1938
Barzun, Jacques, 1907-.
Dec. 14, 1945; Dec. 27, 1945; Mar. 8, 1946
Bates, George Joseph, 1891-1949.
Jan. 30, 1939
Baxter, James Phinney, 1893-.
Nov. 30, 1938
Beard, Charles Austin, 1874-1948.
Jan. 16, 1933
Becker, May (Lamberton), 1873-1958.
Apr. 20, 1935
Belding, Anson W.
Dec. 15, 1944
Beston, Henry.
Mar. 8, 1922; May 4, 1926; Mar. 27, 1929
Bingham, W.V.
Sept. 21, 1910
Bishop, William Warner, 1871-1955.
Nov. 12, 1929; Mar. 26, 1937; Feb. 28, 1944
Bliven, Bruce, 1889-.
May 25, 1938
Boas, Franz, 1858-1942.
Jan. 17, 1919
Bodley, J.H.
1900-1907; 1911-1915; 1918-1920; 1923-1943
Bolton, Charles Knowles, 1867-1950.
Dec. 17, 1926
Bradford, Gamaliel, 1863-1932.
Sept. 26, 1930
Brasch, F.E.
Nov. 25, 1929
Bridgman, Percy Williams, 1882-1961.
Apr. 29, 1943
Briggs, LeBaron Russell, 1855-1934.
1931-1934
Bristow, Gwen, 1903-.
Feb. 10, 1939
Brittain, Vera, 1893?-.
Nov. 3, 1934, Jan. 30, 1939
Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963.
Sept. 15, 1940
Brown, Elmer Ellsworth, 1861-1934.
July 3, 1906
Brown, Henry B., 1847-1917.
Mar. 4, 1908
Brush, Katharine (Ingham), 1902-1952.
Oct. 19, 1928
Bryan, William Lowe, 1860-1955.
June 6, 1908
Buck, Gertrude, 1871-1922.
Mar. 21, 1897; May 16, 1905
Buck, Pearl S., 1892-1973.
July 20, 1942
Burgess, Thornton Waldo, 1874-.
Mar. 15, 1930
Burnham, William Henry, 1855-1941.
May 14, 1912; Jan. 6, 1920
Burritt, Balley Barton, 1878-1954.
Feb. 26, 1908; Jan. 18, 1918; Apr. 13, 1918
Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947.
Dec. 6, 1899
Butterfield, Kenyon Leech, 1868-1935.
Mar. 9, 1911
Cabot, William Brooks, 1858-1949.
Mar. 12, 1930
Canby, Henry Seidel, 1878-1961.
Jan. 6, 1931
Caplan, Abraham.
Apr. 3, 1919
Carhart, Henry Smith, 1844-1920.
Apr. 24, 1908
Carrel, Alexis, 1873-1944.
Nov. 10, 1936
Carroll, Gladys (Hasty), 1904-.
Aug. 28, 1937
Cathcart, C.C.
Jan. 3, 1913
Catlin, George Byron, 1857-1934.
Nov. 26, 1909
Charters, Werrett Wallace, 1875-1952. Oct. 26, 1909
Chase, Mary Ellen, 1887-.
July 15, 1934
Childs, Harold Farnsworth.
Apr. 24, 1909
Churchill, Alfred Vance, 1864-1949.
Nov. 23, 1902
Claxton, Philander Priestley, 1862-1957.
Apr. 8, 1914
Conant, James Bryant, 1893-.
Sept. 23, 1938
Connick, Charles Jay, 1875-1945.
Dec. 17, 1930
Corwin, E.H. Lewinski.
Jan. 9, 1918
Cowley, Malcolm, 1898-.
June 6, 1938; Nov. 11, 1938; Nov. 11, 1942
Cram, Ralph Adams, 1863-1942.
Dec. 15, 1925
Cross, Ira B.
July 10, 1910
Cullen, Countee, 1903-1946.
Jan. 11, 1926; Nov. 21, 1926; Jan. 4, 1927; Jan. 12, 1927; Mar 1, 1927; Mar. 26, 1927; Apr. 3, 1928; Dec. 29, 1929
Cullen, Yolande (DuBois).
May 1, 1928
Dabney, Virginius, 1901-.
Apr. 5, 1939; Jan. 20, 1943
Daly, Arnold, 1875-1927.
Oct. 31, 1905
Dana, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, 1881-1950.
Mar. 15, 1919; Mar. 6, 1930; Mar. 14, 1930
Daniels, Jonathan Worth, 1902-.
Feb. 16, 1936; Jan. 6, 1944
Darden, Colgate Whitehead, 1897-.
Dec. 14, 1942
Davenport, Charles Benedict, 1866-1944.
Apr. 1, 1930
Dawson, Percy M.
Jan. 7, 1929
Deland, Margaret (Campbell), 1857-1945.
Feb. 28, 1924; July 20, 1927; Apr. 17, 1931
Demmon, Isaac Newton, 1842-1920.
Jan. 30, 1896; Feb. 5, 1896; Apr. 11, 1896; Apr. 28, 1896
Deutsch, Babette, 1895-.
Aug. 8, 1945
Dewey, John, 1859-1952.